Rafael Meireles Saback

 $\begin{aligned} & \text{Brazilian} \\ & \text{Warsaw, Poland} \\ & +48\ 728\ 757\ 655 \end{aligned}$

Visa: Has work permit Resume Website rafaelsaback@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/rafael-saback



Summary

Rafael Saback has over 3 years of experience working with robotics research at the Brazilian Institute of Robotics (BIR). During this period, Rafael worked both in Brazil and Germany in an international environment, which helped him develop flexibility and great communication skills. His experience concerns mainly software development in C++ language under a Linux environment. He is fluent in Portuguese, English and Spanish, besides an intermediate knowledge of Polish.

Technical Skills & Tools

- Microstrategy
- C++
- Ruby
- Python
- HTML5

- CSS3
- SQL
- Linux
- Git
- Gi
- Eclipse

- Vim
- Matlab
- Trello (analog to Jira)
- Scrum
- LaTeX

Professional Experience

Microstrategy GDC

August 2017 - Present

Senior Technical Associate

Poland

Participated in Microstrategy's bootcamp and received the following certifications:

- AN 100: Analyst Specialist Bootcamp
- AN 200: MicroStrategy Analyst Master
- AD 100: MicroStrategy Administrator Specialist

Brazilizan Institute of Robotics / SENAI CIMATEC

 \mathbf{Brazil}

August 2013 - December 2016

Underwater Robotics Researcher

Major part of software development was done in C++, while a minor part, especially concerning the system management layer, was done in Ruby. The whole programming was performed in Linux environment.

Member of the team responsible for hardware integration and maintenance, which comprised:

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my job application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the Personal Data Protection Act as of 29 August 1997, consolidated text: Journal of Laws 2016, item 922 as amended.

amended.

- Integration of sensors, thrusters and electronics inside FlatFish;
- Commissioning tests;
- Diagnosis and repair of hardware issues.

Member of the team responsible for software development and integration, which comprised:

- Integration and configuration of sensors such as IMU (RS-232), DVL (RS-232) and Pressure Sensor (RS-232), and actuators, i.e. thrusters (CANopen). The drivers were all developed in C++ language;
- Development of algorithms used to control FlatFish's position (C++);
- Development and integration of software components into the robotics framework (Robot Construction Kit) using Ruby;
- FlatFish's system configuration in Linux environment.

DFKI Germany

July 2014 - July 2015 Guest Researcher

Member of the team responsible for hardware integration, which comprised:

- Integration of sensors, thrusters and computers inside FlatFish;
- Commissioning tests.

Member of the team responsible for software development (C++, Ruby and Linux), which comprised:

- Development of communication driver for Seabotix LBV150;
- Development of control system for dealing with time-delayed underwater vehicles;
- Development of motion model component based on Fossen's model.

Education

• Master in Electrical/Electronic Engineering (2017)

Federal University of Bahia (UFBA) - 2 years

"Robust Nonlinear Model Predictive Control with Fault-Tolerant Control Allocation Applied to an Autonomous Underwater Vehicle"

• Engineer's Degree in Electrical/Electronic Engineering (2013)
Federal University of Bahia (UFBA) - 5 years

"Evaluation of Advanced Control Strategy with Constraints for Stabilization of Severe Slug Flow"

Language Skills

- Portuguese: native language
- English: fluent (language course in Vancouver)
- Spanish: fluent (1 year in Spain as an interchange student)
- Polish: intermediate (language course in Warsaw)